#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

#### Mahlet Demeke Wolde



💡 Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

+251939338005

mahletdemeke0791@gmail.com

Sex F | Date of birth 14/06/1999 G.C | Nationality Ethiopian

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Skilled and dedicated Engineer, with exceptional theoretical knowledge and practical experience visa-vis Electronic and Computer systems. Committed to providing excellent service and care to my clients, listening to each of their concerns, and providing solutions transcending system limitations. Utilizing effective communication skills, developed through my leadership roles in academia and practicum, I am able to address clients' concerns explicitly. I rely on teamwork to provide all-rounded service.

#### QUALIFICATION

Electronic and Computer Engineer

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Oct,2018 – Jun,2022 Hawassa University Institute of Technology

Oct, 2021 - Feb, 2022 Internship, Information and network security Agency (INSA), Ethiopia

#### **Key Responsibilities**

- Practiced on Java EE Full-stack development.
- Developed management system using Prime-face interface on Windows platform.
- Practiced installation of Ubuntu on Virtual Box.
- Practiced basic switch configuration procedures including V-LAN.
- Performed setup-ping Digital Signage
- Performed various design on Cisco packet tracer
- Discussed Types of Network Cable and Network device types
- Practiced Crimping UTP Cable
- Practiced Splicing Fiber Optic Cable
- Took online course on Fortinet NSE Academy.
- Discussed network installation, Routing, diagnostic results, maintenance of computer systems with senior technicians, proposed troubleshoot of problems.
- Kept thorough researches related to networking.

#### Oct,2018-Jun,2022

#### Hawassa University Institute of Technology, Hawassa, Ethiopia.

#### Bachelor of Science(CGPA: 3.13)

- Main Courses: Software Engineering, Data communication and Computer Network, Data structure and algorithm, Database System, Computer Programming, Operating System and Cryptography-Network Security.
- Semester-project: Automated Dormitory light Controlling System
- Internship-project:Hosting company Health center management System
- BSC-Project:Interlinked Hospital Management System

#### **TRAININGS**

- Computer Hardware and Software Maintenance by Rehobot Institute of Technology
- Mastering Arduino and Micro controller by Hawassa University
- Certified with Java and Java EE programming languages
- > Women Empowerment Program by Jot self development program
- ➤ Life Skill

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

#### Languages

Amharic : Native English : Very Good

#### Organizational / managerial skills

- School Representative for 3 Years
- Ability to remain calm, think clearly, and act quickly in a stressful environment.
- data analysis to improve quality in clients' care.
- Ability to cultivate team work spirit.
- Good communication skills

#### Software skills

- ▶ Proficient in Microsoft Office<sup>TM</sup>
- Windows, OS, Linux Operating System
- Good command of modeling and simulating Software Matlab, Cisco-Packet Tracer, Multism and Proteus
- Good command of office suite (word processor, spread sheet, Presentation software)

Projects:

Design of a Hospitals web-based applications using Java EE, Automation of Dormitory using Arduino and Pic-micro controller with C language and Face detector door-locking with Raspberry-Pi.

References:

Abraham Sisay (MSc), Information Network Security Agency (INSA)

- +251 912959163
- abrshtipical@gmail.com

Abeto Alemu (MSc), Hawassa University Institute of Technology

- +251 910113191
- abetoalemu@hu.edu.et



HIoT

Hawassa Institute of Technology ቴከኖሎጂ ኢኒስቲትየት Hawassa University ሃዋሳ የኒቬርቲ

## School of Electrical & Computer Engineering

የኤሌክትሪካልና ኮምፒውተር ምህንድስና ት/ቤት

Date: 06/07/2022

#### Dear Sir/Madam,

This recommendation letter is written on behalf of Ms. Mahlet Demeke, who was student in Hawassa University, Electrical and Computer Engineering department, where I was instructor in the department.

I was her instructor for courses Database System, Programming Language and Software Engineering. As her instructor and advisor, I would rate Mahlet's overall performance in these subjects is great. This is evidenced by her grades and projects.

She has been in computer stream in the department and she was hard working, communicative, and active student in her stay. She had shown her qualities in group work, problem solving and in integrating theoretical knowledge with practical application. In her personal conduct, she was decent, honest, time conscious.

With complete and organized documentation, her thesis was one of the outstanding ones. Based upon this, I rate her skills excellent.

Therefore, I highly recommend that you consider Mahlet's application, as She will be a great asset to your program.

In the case any information is required. Please do not hesitate to contact me

Sincerely,

Abeto Alemu

Email: abetoalemu@la.edu.et

Tel: +251-910-11-31-91, Hawassa University, Ethiopia

Website: http://www.hu.edu.et

≥ 5 Awassa, Ethiopia

# ሀዋሳ ዩኒቨርሲቲ

Tel: 046-220-96-76/77 -220-02-29 -202-03-41



## HAWASSA UNIVERSITY

Fax: 046-2-21 47 81 Website: www.hu.edu.et P.O.Box 05, Hawassa, Ethiopia

Date: July 04, 2022 G.C.



### TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN



This is to certify that

#### MAHLET DEMEKE WOLDE

Graduated From Hawassa University

With

Bachelor of Science Degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering (Computer Engineering)

CGPA: 3.13

June 29, 2022 GC

Issuance of original diploma and transcript awaits settlements of cost-sharing expenses or provision of the required services.

Zeri/Registrar

Registrar & Alun

Directorate Director